Guide to the Pat Finelli Photographs, 1962-1970 and undated RL.00393
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pat Finelli photographs
1962-1970 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Finelli, Pat.
RL.00393
4.5 Linear Feet
Pat Finelli (1927-1970) was a free-lance commercial photographer in New York during the 1960s who worked for a number of New York advertising agencies, including J. Walter Thompson, Compton, and Erwin, Wasey, Ruthrauf & Ryan. The Pat Finelli Photographs span the years 1962-1970 and include photographs, negatives, slides, transparencies and print advertisements that document Finelli's work for advertising agencies including J. Walter Thompson and Erwin, Wasey, Ruthrauf & Ryan. Companies featured include BMW, First National City Bank, Ford, Lederle, Mack, Mercury outboard, Pet and Procter & Gamble. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
2600 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Pat Finelli Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Biographical Note
Pat Finelli was born in 1927 and grew up in Brooklyn, N.Y. He served in the Navy as a medic and later worked as a photographer in New York, eventually opening his own studio. Finelli worked on advertising campaigns for a number of New York advertising agencies, including J. Walter Thompson, Erwin Wasey Ruthrauf & Ryan, and Compton Advertising. He received numerous advertising industry awards for his photography, including selection as one of the Top Fifty Advertisements of the Year in 1964, as well as a Certificate of Excellence from the American Institute of Graphic Arts, for his work on Mack Trucks for Erwin Wasey agency. At the 44th annual exhibition of the Art Directors Club of New York in 1965, Finelli received an Award of Distinctive Merit and a Certificate of Merit. Finelli also taught photography at the Parsons School of Design, part of the New School University. Finelli died in New York in 1970.
Collection Overview
The Pat Finelli Photographs span the years 1962-1970 and include photographs, negatives, slides, transparencies and print advertisements that document Finelli's work for advertising agencies including J. Walter Thompson and Erwin, Wasey, Ruthrauf & Ryan. Companies featured include BMW, First National City Bank, Ford, Lederle, Mack, Mercury, Pet and Procter & Gamble.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged by format: Slides, Negatives, Transparencies, Mounted Photographs, and Print Advertisements.
Related Material
Related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
JWT Competitive Advertisements
JWT Domestic Advertisements
JWT Iconographic Collection
Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements
Photographs; Commercial photography -- United States; Negatives (photographic); Slides (photographs); Advertising photography -- United States; Commercial photography; Advertising -- Photographers -- United States; Advertising photography; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Photographers; Advertising; Mack Trucks, Inc.; Pet Milk Company; Procter & Gamble Company; Bayerische Motoren Werke; First National City Bank (New York, N.Y.); Finelli, Pat.; Finelli, Pat, (1927-1970); Brunswick Corporation. Mercury Marine; Lederle Laboratories; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; Ford Motor Company
- Pat Finelli Photographs, 1962-1970 and undated
  - Slides
    - Beverage, 1964 Aug. (Box 1)
    - Boat, 1969 Nov. (Box 1)
    - Boat add, 1969 Nov. (Box 1)
    - Boat add C, 1969 Nov., 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add fishing, 1969 Nov., 7 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add left, 1969 Nov., 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add Neil, 1969 Nov., 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add Raper, 1969 Nov., 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add Rebollo, 1969 Nov., 7 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat add SW, 1969 Nov., 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Boat left, 1969 Nov. (Box 1)
    - Boat marina, 1969 Nov., 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Boat SW (Box 2)
    - Circus, 1962-1965 and undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Commercial, 1969 Apr. (Box 2)
    - Dancing, undated (Box 2)
    - Kodak--Belly dancer, undated (Box 2)
    - Mack Truck, 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Mercury Outboard, 2 Proj show, 1969 Dec. (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 and undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - New Orleans, undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Singer on stage, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Trucks, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Unedited slides (Box 2)
    - Couple eating, undated (Box 2)
    - Couple with guitar, undated (Box 2)
    - Couple with motorcycle, undated (Box 2)
    - Couple, striped dress, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
  - Negatives
    - EWR&R, F1210, Allentown Mack Truck, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, Ford (Falcon, Fairlane 500), 1306, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, Italy, 1289, FNCB (First National City Bank), undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, Nevada, 1293, FNCB, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, Portugal, 1289, FNCB, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, San Francisco, 1293, FNCB, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, Spain, 1289, FNCB, undated (Box 3)
    - JWT, World's Fair, F-1090, circa 1964 (Box 3)
    - Lee Tailor, Rome Pers., 1289, undated (Box 3)
    - Never Before...And Never Again, undated (Box 3)
  - Transparencies, undated (Box 4)
  - Oversize Materials
    - Mounted advertisements (Box 5)
      - Lederle Ledercort D, undated (Box 5)
      - Pet, Sego, undated (Box 5)
      - Procter & Gamble, Tide detergent, undated (Box 5)
    - Mounted photographs (Mack truck, portraits, outdoor), undated (Box 5)
    - Print advertisements
      - Alcoa, undated (Box 5)
      - BMW, 1969 and undated (Box 5)
      - Eastman Kodak, 1969 and undated (Box 5)
      - First National City Bank, 1966 and undated (Box 5)
      - General Mills, Total cereal, 1967 (Box 5)
      - Henry McKenna bourbon, 1968 (Box 5)
      - Mack Truck, 1964 (Box 5)
      - Mercury Outboard, circa 1970 (Box 5)
      - Pet, Sego, 1967 (Box 5)
      - Procter & Gamble, Thrill detergent, 1968 (Box 5)